<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 15:13:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Easily strengthen your shop’s security</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/easily-strengthen-shops-security/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/easily-strengthen-shops-security/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 15:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quentin Audrain]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20407</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop evolves every day with the aim to always put the merchant at the center of our decisions. Whether it’s the development of new features, the establishment of a new user experience or security improvements, this work is carried out continuously with the Community. That’s why we would like to talk with you about safety [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/easily-strengthen-shops-security/">Easily strengthen your shop’s security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop evolves every day with the aim to always put the merchant at the center of our decisions. Whether it’s the development of new features, the establishment of a new user experience or security improvements, this work is carried out continuously with the Community.</p>
<p>That’s why we would like to talk with you about safety and we strongly encourage you to read all these information carefully to improve your shop security.<br />
In addition to being good practices to follow, these simple tips will make your store more secure and more able to receive the security update we will announce soon.<br />
<span id="more-20407"></span><br />
<strong>UPGRADE YOUR SHOP</strong><br />
This may seem obvious but it&#8217;s an important reminder! When was your last update? Indeed, it is important to note that a new version of PrestaShop can provide security updates in addition to fixes and new features.</p>
<p><strong>ADD A SECOND PASSWORD WITH A .HTACCESS FILE</strong><br />
In extra to your current login page, you can add a second level of security to access your back office, by setting up a password using a .htaccess file. This double safety allows you to set a second login and password known only by you. You’ll have to give it before you even get to the back office login page.<br />
Nothing could be simpler, follow the steps as <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Making+your+PrestaShop+installation+more+secure" target="_blank">explained in our documentation</a>.</p>
<p><strong>USE COMPLEX PASSWORDS</strong><br />
Of course, avoid easy passwords, like the name of your pet or the date of birth of your first child. You need a really complex and unique password for your shop. The safest is to use a sequence of letters, numbers and special characters or a <a href="http://www.fourmilab.ch/javascrypt/pass_phrase.html" target="_blank">passphrase</a> (For example: D37htyoB4!17 or Oh!That’saVERYniceboat! 17 or even &#8220;I have no idea.&#8221;).</p>
<p><strong>CHANGE THE ADMIN FILE NAME</strong><br />
When you install PrestaShop, you manage your shop via your back office. This back office is itself accessible via an address defined by a folder on your server. By default, it is renamed to &#8220;admin + number&#8221;, for example admin42. Take the time to rename this file on your server with a name that is unique to you or better, a random sequence of numbers and letters. Your back office will then be accessible to an address as follow: myshop.com/5Ghtsf4k</p>
<p>Well done, your shop is already more secure and that after only a few minutes of work. So please, share these tips with your merchants friends!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/easily-strengthen-shops-security/">Easily strengthen your shop’s security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/easily-strengthen-shops-security/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>8 tricks for writing a great blog post</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-tricks-writing-great-blog-post/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-tricks-writing-great-blog-post/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20390</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>An estimated 53.6 million new posts appear per month on WordPress alone. Why even start a blog with so much competing noise out there? Because a business blog for your ecommerce store is a great way to establish relationships with customers in a non-sales context. Good blog content engages by solving problems and informing readers. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-tricks-writing-great-blog-post/">8 tricks for writing a great blog post</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An estimated <strong>53.6 million new posts</strong> appear per month on WordPress alone. Why even start a blog with so much competing noise out there?</p>
<p>Because a business blog for your ecommerce store is a great way to establish relationships with customers in a non-sales context. Good blog content engages by solving problems and informing readers. Your business meets a unique customer need and your blog should speak to that. If it does, and you follow the advice below, you’ll increase your chances of standing out from the 53, 599,000,000 other posts going up this month, and you just might gain a few new customers.<br />
<span id="more-20390"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">1 Get to know your audience</h2>
<p>Before you start writing anything, ask yourself these two questions:</p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">Why am I writing this?</span><br />
Your business goal may be to get sales leads, but the primary goal of your blog is to inform your readers and give them advice to solve a problem. In this way, you can use your blog to build authority and trust, which you’ll need to attract and retain customers.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">Who is my audience?</span><br />
You should have created <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">customer personas</a> when you started building your business. Get them out and keep them in mind when you’re writing. This will help you get into your ideal customer’s head and write TO them: what are they interested in? What are their problems? What kind of tone do they react to, ie highly technical or casual and relaxed?</p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">2 Have a conversation</h2>
<p>Once you know who you’re talking to, think about how you’re going to talk to them. A blog should be friendly and engaging, practical and easy to navigate</p>
<p>- <span style="font-style: italic">Get to the point:</span> Your readers are busy people, so show that you value their time by getting straight to the point. Favor the active tense and be concise: don’t use ten words when you can use five.</p>
<p>- <span style="font-style: italic">Keep it simple:</span> you’re here to make your customers’ lives easier by providing expert help, not to show off your expansive vocabulary. Avoid industry jargon and long, rambling introductions or side-notes.</p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">3 Inform, don’t sell</h2>
<p>People are bombarded with sales messages from the time they wake up to the time they slip back into bed at night. Chances are, they’re not coming to your site to read another pitch. They’re going to be asking themselves ‘What’s in it for me?’, so make sure you have a compelling response. Develop blog content that gives something to your reader: the answer to a question, the solution to a problem, a piece of information they didn’t know.</p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">4 Craft catchy headlines and tweet-able titles</h2>
<p>Headlines and subtitles have a dual role: to attract curious readers and push your blog to the top of search engine rankings. Short, to-the-point titles are easy to share on social media, where you can generate conversation and engagement around your blog.</p>
<p>Think about using evocative, sensory words, or incorporating questions that pique interest. Numbers have been found to attract clicks, but they’ve been heavily used to the point of being annoying, so use them sparingly and always with a compelling theme connected to your business, e.g. “7 tips for a good night’s sleep” if you sell bedding.</p>
<p>Here’s an external resource with a list of websites that have great title generators: <a href="http://smallbiztrends.com/2014/11/generate-article-titles-work.html" target="_blank">http://smallbiztrends.com/2014/11/generate-article-titles-work.html</a></p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">5 Structure your ideas</h2>
<p>No one likes sifting through a rambling jumble of text online. Make it easy for your readers to follow your train of thought and pick out the information that they need. Try these tips:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Use subtitles to organize your ideas</li>
<li>Divide body text into digestible paragraphs</li>
<li>Use bullets for easy-to-scan lists</li>
</ul>
<p>And remember, ALWAYS check grammar and spelling. Not only will this make your writing pop, it will reassure your readers about your professionalism.</p>
<p>Use related images to break up text and add an attractive visual elements. Photos, drawings and diagrams can also be great ways to explain complex ideas.</p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">6 Use keywords</h2>
<p>Before you begin writing, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/find-the-right-seo-keywords-for-your-online-store/">make a list of keyword</a> related to your business and the subject you’re tackling. Keep them in mind as you write and try to incorporate them judiciously throughout your text, especially in titles and subtitles. Over time, and coupled with reader engagement&#8211;comments and social sharing&#8211;keywords will help you rank higher in search engines.</p>
<p>Be wary of using too many keywords&#8211;you’re writing for people, not search engines&#8211;and never, ever copy and paste text from your own blog or other sites. Duplicate content will get you into <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/knock-google-panda-seo-best-practices-prestashop/" target="_blank">major trouble with Google</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">7 Go Out on a Bang</h2>
<p>Before signing off, recap the main takeaways for your readers and include a call to action. This is where you might be able to slip in something related to your sales goal, like getting readers to sign up for your newsletter or check out a related product page.</p>
<p>Here are some suggestions for writing calls to action:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Ask readers a question to encourage comments and shares.</li>
<li>Use engaging text that asks a question.</li>
<li>Give a clear direction of what you want the reader to do next.</li>
<li>Create a sense of urgency.</li>
<li>Focus on the benefits.</li>
<li>Embed call to action in link. You can be creative if it’s appropriate and clear.</li>
</ul>
<p>…and most importantly…</p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">8 Be consistent</h2>
<p>Creating and maintaining a business blog takes a lot of time and energy, but you don’t have to commit to writing an article every day from the beginning. Build a healthy blog by posting regularly, even if it’s only once a week. You can use newsletters and social media to inform your community about new posts. Just remember, once you start the machine, you have to keep it running!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-complete-introduction-to-ecommerce-blogging/">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-complete-introduction-to-ecommerce-blogging/</a></p>
<p>An old blog post with more information about creating an editorial calendar which helps with consistency <img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<h2 style="color: #29bad7">Key Takeaways</h2>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Post on a consistent schedule</li>
<li>Tailor content and tone to your audience</li>
<li>Write posts that deliver value to your readers</li>
<li>Structure content for readability</li>
<li>Run spell check!</li>
<li>Finish on a call to action</li>
</ul>
<p>Do you have a business blog? What works for you? What doesn’t?<br />
Don’t have a blog yet? Start one today with this premium module: <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/content-management/4731-professional-blog.html" target="_blank">http://addons.prestashop.com/en/content-management/4731-professional-blog.html</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-tricks-writing-great-blog-post/">8 tricks for writing a great blog post</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-tricks-writing-great-blog-post/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Themes vs Custom development: Why templates are awesome</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/themes-vs-custom-development-templates-awesome/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/themes-vs-custom-development-templates-awesome/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 07:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20376</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>There are countless ways to decorate and design your online shop. You can use the default template that comes included with the software, purchase a theme from PrestaShop Addons, or hire a web developer for custom development. Although each option is great for customizing your online storefront, they each have their pros and cons. To [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/themes-vs-custom-development-templates-awesome/">Themes vs Custom development: Why templates are awesome</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are countless ways to decorate and design your online shop. You can use the <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/">default template</a> that comes included with the software, purchase a theme from <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Addons</a>, or <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partnershttps:/www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">hire a web developer</a> for custom development. Although each option is great for customizing your online storefront, they each have their pros and cons.</p>
<p>To highlight the benefits of each option, we’ve asked the people who know best. In today’s article, we’re talking with Maxim Kiryanov from PrestaShop Addon’s premium theme designer, <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/36_template-monster" target="_blank">Template Monster</a>. Read on for his expert opinion on why templates are awesome.<br />
<span id="more-20376"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #d39c4c">1. Themes save time</h2>
<p>You’ve heard the saying, “time is money.” Well, templates help you do just that by helping you customize your shop at lighting fast speeds. Depending on the level of customization you want to make, you can update the look and feel of your shop in under one hour.</p>
<p>First time you’re installing a theme? Don’t worry about not being familiar with the process. Even without coding, web design and development skills, you can get your shop looking the way you want within a week. Template Monster provides countless <a href="http://www.templatemonster.com/help/prestashop-1-6-x-how-to-install-the-template-to-prestashop-cloud-hosting.html" target="_blank">manuals and tutorials</a> that walk you through the process of installing your first theme.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d39c4c">2. Templates save money</h2>
<p>The average theme costs about $144.99 (+ taxes). This is a fraction of what it would cost to have a web development company build your online shop. Along with the theme, you’ll also get the original .psd and other image files that can be customized to fit your shop. These images will help you launch your shop faster and the images can be used later as a template for future images.</p>
<p>The best deal you’ll get is the access to 24/7 pro support from Template Monster. “We work even on New Year’s Eve.” Maxim adds, “And that’s not a joke.” They know entrepreneur don’t take holidays, so neither do they! They’re on stand-by to help you customize your shop to match your shop’s branding.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d39c4c">3. Themes offer great designs</h2>
<p>The best thing about purchasing a module is the design. Template Monster’s premium themes are developed according to PrestaShop’s requirements. Additionally, they include <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-ecommerce-design-trends-2015/">the latest design trends</a> like parallax scrolling, moving backgrounds and large images.<br />
Having created more than 50,000 PrestaShop themes, they’re experts at creating gorgeous and modern designs that match every type of product niche. There is a variety of professionally designed themes for any kind of business project. Everything from <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/interior-furniture/18247-kitchen-supplies-store.html" target="_blank">Kitchen Supplies</a> to <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/food-drinks/18355-cigar-smoking.html" target="_blank">eCigars</a>, you’ll find an option for your business niche, no matter what type of shop you plan on running.</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-6"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20378" alt="ecigarettes" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/ecigarettes-546x1024.jpg" width="546" height="1024" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-6"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20377" alt="kitchen" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/kitchen-323x1024.jpg" width="323" height="1024" /></div>
</div>
<h2 style="color: #d39c4c">4. Templates simplify shop launches.</h2>
<p>Setting up an online store is no easy task. Using a template simplifies the process of launching your online store. You don’t have to do your own research about optimizing product and landing pages. All these considerations are already built into the template you purchase.<br />
Even if you decide to customize the theme, having an optimized design expedites the process. Unlike custom development, there is no downtime. Each theme has already been tested. All you have to do is pick the right one for your shop.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d39c4c">In a Nutshell</h2>
<p>The top reasons to purchase a template is time and money. Compared to custom development or DIY design, you’ll have a gorgeous storefront in no time. In addition to time and money, themes are created with the best development practices so your shop is optimized for conversions.</p>
<p>Not quite convinced that themes are right for your online store? Stay tuned for our next blog as we interview a web developer. They’ll share their side of this battle. Already using a theme on your shop? Tell us why you chose to use themes in the comments below!</p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/36_template-monster" target="_blank">About Template Monster:</a></p>
<p>Template Monster is one of the oldest template companies around. Since opening their business in 2002, they’ve designed over 50,000 different templates. Since 2010, they have released more than 1,000 PrestaShop Themes. See more from <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/36_template-monster" target="_blank">Template Monster</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/themes-vs-custom-development-templates-awesome/">Themes vs Custom development: Why templates are awesome</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/themes-vs-custom-development-templates-awesome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>20 PrestaShop features you haven&#8217;t discovered</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/20-prestashop-features-havent-discovered/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/20-prestashop-features-havent-discovered/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 09:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20367</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that PrestaShop’s native software has over 300 features? Whether you’ve been using our software for years or just opened your online store, we’d like to help you make the most of our shopping cart software by sharing 20 PrestaShop features you (probably) haven’t discovered. Read on to find out what they are! [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/20-prestashop-features-havent-discovered/">20 PrestaShop features you haven&#8217;t discovered</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that PrestaShop’s native software has over 300 features? Whether you’ve been using our software for years or just opened your online store, we’d like to help you make the most of our shopping cart software by sharing 20 PrestaShop features you (probably) haven’t discovered. Read on to find out what they are!<br />
<span id="more-20367"></span><br />
PrestaShop’s features help you, as an online merchant, sell more and run your business more efficiently. Today we’ll break down these lesser-known features into the following categories: operations, marketing and customer engagement, front office features and shop improvement. We’ll also show you how to configure them. Just keep in mind, these features are available in version PrestaShop 1.6.0.14 or after.</p>
<h2 style="color:#345c64">Operations</h2>
<p>At the core of every online shop are its business operations. These features help improve your back office interface and let you specify which notifications you want to receive, so you can run your business efficiently. </p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">1. Receive email notifications when a new order is placed.</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">MODULES &gt; Administration &gt; Mail Alerts &gt; (Install &gt;) Configure &gt; New Order: Yes &gt; Email Address: name@yourshop.com &gt; Save</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">2. Change the theme and color of your back office.</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">ADMINISTRATION &gt; Employees &gt; Employee Name &gt; Theme<br />
Or, select your name from the upper right corner &gt; My preferences</p>
<p>Pick from:</p>
<ol>
<li>Default: Green and Grey</li>
<li>Blue: Light Blue and Dark Blue</li>
<li>Contrast: Light Blue and Gray</li>
<li>Flex: Turquoise and Gray</li>
<li>Fruit: Dark Blue and Gray</li>
<li>Prune: Purple and Dark Blue</li>
</ol>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">3. Quickly access any webpage from your notifications bar.</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">Navigate to the page you want to bookmark &gt; From the Quick Access tab on the top menu, click “+ Add current page to Quick Access” &gt; “Update successful” confirmation.</p>
<p>Now you can easily access this page anytime from the Quick Access drop down. </p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">4. Move your menu back up to the top of your website </h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">ADMINISTRATION &gt; Employees &gt; Click Employee Name &gt; Admin menu orientation: Top</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">5. Modify date and time formula. </h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">LOCALIZATION &gt; Languages &gt; Select the language you’d like to edit &gt; Date format &amp; Date format (full) &gt; Use the instructions to edit the date format</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">6. Expedite bulk uploads by downloading our sample CSV. </h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">ADVANCED PARAMETERS &gt; CSV Import &gt; Download Sample CSV Files</p>
<p>Tip: These CSV files are delimited by “;”.</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">7. Turn off new order notifications at any time. </h4>
<p>Don’t like the new order counter on your dashboard? Turn it off any time.</p>
<p style="font-style: italic">ADMINISTRATION &gt; Preferences &gt; Notification &gt; Show notifications for new orders,  customers or messages: No.</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">8. Make reordering a breeze with a list of sold out and low inventory products. </h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">STATS &gt; Stats &gt; Catalog evaluation</p>
<h2 style="color:#345c64">Front Office Features</h2>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">9. Protect your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/diy-ecommerce-guide-to-gorgeous-product-photography/">product images</a> with watermarks.</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">MODULES &gt; Administration &gt; Watermark &gt;</p>
<p>Upload a .gif version of your watermark.<br />
Set the opacity.<br />
Indicate  how and where you want it positioned.<br />
Select which images you want to watermark.</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">10. Upload a custom image for when a product has no image.</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">LOCALIZATION &gt; Languages &gt; Select Language &gt; “No Picture” Image</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">11. Upload custom color swatches to show detail or prints. </h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">CATALOG &gt; Product Attributes &gt; Color &gt; Add New Values &gt; Name and upload your new custom color.</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">12. Upload a custom image for the store locator map.</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">PREFERENCES &gt; Themes &gt; Your Current Theme &gt; Icons &gt; Upload a new icon.</p>
<p>Suggested size: 30 x 30 pixels<br />
	File type: Gif</p>
<h2 style="color:#345c64">Marketing and Customer Engagement</h2>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">13. Modify your confirmation <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/">email template</a> (and others too!)</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">LOCALIZATION &gt; Translations &gt; Type of Translation: Email templates &gt; Select your theme &gt; Select the language</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">14. Modify your shop’s voice to speak to your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/examples-of-ecommerce-marketing-emails-that-work/">target personas</a>. </h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">LOCALIZATION &gt; Translations &gt; Type of Translation: Front Office &gt; Select your theme &gt; Select the language</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">15. Welcome customers to your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/8-tips-for-a-successful-email-campaign/">newsletter program</a> with a discount code. </h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">MODULES &gt; Front Office Feature &gt; Newsletter block &gt; (Install &gt;) Configure &gt; Welcome voucher code: Code name</p>
<p>To complete the setup, you need to create and activate the new voucher code. Be sure that this code matches the the code name in the emails. </p>
<p style="font-style: italic">PRICE RULES &gt; Cart Rules &gt; Add new cart rule &gt; follow the on-screen instructions.</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">16. Edit your homepage’s <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/find-the-right-seo-keywords-for-your-online-store/">meta information to improve SEO</a>. </h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">PREFERENCES &gt; SEO &amp; URLs &gt; “Select Index”</p>
<p>Add meta information and the page title to improve your SEO for those keywords.</p>
<h2 style="color:#345c64">Shop Improvement</h2>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">17. View a list of <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-essential-tips-to-improving-your-on-site-search-engine/">on-site search queries</a> from customers.</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">STATS &gt; Stats&gt; Shop Search</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">18. Access order information from <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-time-tested-ways-to-reduce-abandoned-shopping-carts/">abandoned carts</a>.</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">CUSTOMERS &gt; Shopping Carts &gt; Click on any cart for detailed information.</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">19. Forecast sales directly from the dashboard</h4>
<p style="font-style: italic">DASHBOARD &gt; Forecast Table &gt; click the configuration icon.</p>
<p>Enter your projected sales information. The chart will be automatically updated with the latest sales to show whether or not you’re meeting your projections.</p>
<h4 style="color:#589ca9">20. <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-hire-your-first-employees-for-your-online-store/">Expanding your team</a>? Give each team member an individual log in. </h4>
<p>As you add new team members, ensure they only have access to the features and functionality they need, we’ve pre-configured permissions for new employees in sales, translation and shipping operations. </p>
<p style="font-style: italic">ADMINISTRATION &gt; Employees &gt; Add New Employees &gt; Fill in the information and assign a role.</p>
<p>Which of these features did you just learn about? Which did you already know about? Know any other secret features that didn’t make our top 20 list? Share them in the comments below. Not familiar with PrestaShop? Learn all about <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-templates">PrestaShop’s features</a>. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/20-prestashop-features-havent-discovered/">20 PrestaShop features you haven&#8217;t discovered</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/20-prestashop-features-havent-discovered/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Transparency in Cross-Border Transactions</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/importance-transparency-cross-border-transactions/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/importance-transparency-cross-border-transactions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 14:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20359</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In today’s post, we welcome Diane Callihan, Marketing Content Strategist for Bongo International, a FedEx company. She’s going to shed some light on the complexities of shipping internationally. Worldwide e-commerce is growing at exponential rates, and more and more US e-retailers are realizing that selling and shipping their products globally offers vast potential to grow [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/importance-transparency-cross-border-transactions/">The Importance of Transparency in Cross-Border Transactions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-style:italic">In today’s post, we welcome Diane Callihan, Marketing Content Strategist for Bongo International, a FedEx company. She’s going to shed some light on the complexities of shipping internationally.</span></p>
<p>Worldwide e-commerce is growing at exponential rates, and more and more US e-retailers are realizing that selling and shipping their products globally offers vast potential to grow their businesses.</p>
<p>In fact, according to eMarketer, worldwide B2C e-commerce sales hit $1.5 trillion in 2014, and are predicted to reach $2.35 trillion by 2017.</p>
<p>Still, some merchants have been reluctant to join the global marketplace due to strict cross-border regulations and the complexities of doing business in multiple countries. One of the challenges to global e-commerce is understanding duties, taxes and custom fees around the world.<br />
<span id="more-20359"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#2ca0b9">Duties, Taxes &amp; Customs Fees</h2>
<p>Almost all shipments crossing international borders are subject to duties and taxes imposed by the importing country&#8217;s government. Duties and taxes are imposed to generate revenue, protect local industries against foreign competition, or both.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://www.export.gov/">Export.gov</a>, a tariff or duty (the words are used interchangeably) is a tax levied by governments based on the value of imported products, including freight and insurance. Different tariffs are applied to different products by different countries. National sales and local taxes, and in some instances customs fees, will often be charged in addition to the tariff.</p>
<p>These costs add to the merchant’s product costs, which can negatively influence foreign buyers.</p>
<p>Some countries have very high duties and taxes; some are relatively low. If a merchant’s product is primarily made in the US with US-originating components, it may qualify for duty-free entry into countries with which the US has a <a href="http://export.gov/fta" target="_blank">free trade agreement</a> (FTA). The US currently has FTAs with more than 20 countries.</p>
<p>Duties and taxes on international shipments are based on a number of factors, including the value of the item being shipped, how the product is used, the country of origin, any trade agreements between the origin and destination country, and the product’s Harmonized System (HS) code.</p>
<h2 style="color:#2ca0b9">Harmonized System Codes</h2>
<p>The International Harmonized System is a commodity-classification system administered by the World Customs Administration. Countries around the globe use this international classification for all imported and exported goods. Every item that is shipped is legally required to have a 6-digit HS code, whether it’s a paper clip or a jet engine. The first two digits generally categorize the item, the second two classify it further, and the third two are most specific.</p>
<p>In addition to the HS code, each country may add additional numbers to the end of the HS Code to specify the item even further. The US uses a 10-digit code known as a Schedule B number. The first 6 digits of the Schedule B number are the HS code, followed by 4 digits for further classification.</p>
<p>Tariffs or duties are often assigned, in part, based on these classification codes. To get a duty rate for importing products into a foreign country, one needs to have the complete classification number used by the importing country. </p>
<p>A good global e-commerce solution provider will determine the classification codes for every product/SKU a merchant sells, as well as logging in the item’s dimensions and weight. With that information, as well as the destination country, they can determine not only the shipping cost of any item, but also any applicable duties, fees or taxes.</p>
<p>Together, this is called the total landed cost. Clearly a lot of variables go into this cost, so it pays to work with an expert who can help navigate international logistics.</p>
<h2 style="color:#2ca0b9">Why is the Total Landed Cost Important?</h2>
<p>According to a study by the <span style="font-style:italic">Baymard Institute</span>, the average documented online shopping cart abandonment rate is 68%. <span>Econsultancy</span> reported in April of 2014 that global retailers are losing $3 trillion (USD) in sales every year from abandoned carts.</p>
<p>The number one reason for shopping cart abandonment (56%) is that buyers get frustrated when presented with unexpected costs, including shipping, duties and taxes.<br />
Due to laws and regulations around the world, those costs are unavoidable for international consumers. So how can eRetailers make those costs more palatable to their global customers?</p>
<p>Transparency.</p>
<p>Being able to calculate and communicate the &#8220;landed&#8221; cost up-front can often save both the merchant and the consumer valuable time and money.  The merchant can find out which of their products will cost the most in shipping and taxes and adjust pricing accordingly.</p>
<p>And the consumer will be informed throughout the checkout process, so there will be no surprises at the end.</p>
<p>Greg Sack, Managing Director of E-commerce for Bongo International (A FedEx Company) said, “We believe that transparency at checkout is vital. E-commerce merchants benefit from being upfront with their customers throughout the process, and international consumers are more likely to buy if they aren’t surprised by hidden fees or unexpected charges.”</p>
<p>Determining and sharing the total landed costs of products can help merchants inform their international customers, and ultimately, retain sales.</p>
<hr width="25%" align="left" />
Diane Callihan is the Marketing Content Strategist for Bongo International, A FedEx Company. Founded in 2007, Bongo International began as a package-forwarding service for international consumers and expanded to develop global e-commerce solutions for online merchants. Today, they are a leader in cross-border technologies enabling merchants to tap into the vast potential of world markets.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/importance-transparency-cross-border-transactions/">The Importance of Transparency in Cross-Border Transactions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/importance-transparency-cross-border-transactions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How can you start using A/B testing on a site with low traffic?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/can-start-using-ab-testing-site-low-traffic/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/can-start-using-ab-testing-site-low-traffic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 13:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20347</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today we&#8217;re pleased to bring you an article by Alix de Sagazan, the cofounder of AB Tasty, leaders in A/B testing and personalization. She explains to us how sites with low traffic can benefit from A/B testing. It seems unthinkable today to try to optimize your site&#8217;s conversion rate without using A/B testing. Yet according [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/can-start-using-ab-testing-site-low-traffic/">How can you start using A/B testing on a site with low traffic?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today we&#8217;re pleased to bring you an article by Alix de Sagazan, the cofounder of AB Tasty, leaders in A/B testing and personalization. She explains to us how sites with low traffic can benefit from A/B testing. It seems unthinkable today to try to optimize your site&#8217;s conversion rate without using A/B testing.</p>
<p>Yet according to best practices, the conditions required to run an effective testing campaign can make it seem like it&#8217;s only for high-traffic sites. Yes, visitor numbers and conversions are determining factors, but does that mean A/B testing is pointless if your traffic is too low?<br />
<span id="more-20347"></span><br />
Luckily, that&#8217;s not the case! You can get all the benefits of an A/B test campaign even if your site has low traffic. There&#8217;s only one limitation to keep in mind with this type of site: statistical reliability. For a test to be considered reliable, the statistical reliability must be above 95%. Below that level, data is not be guaranteed to be reliable, and so it would be risky to draw any hasty conclusions from it. So the only limitation is reaching that level of reliability. The time it takes to get there can vary depending on site traffic, the number of pages tested, the initial conversion rate, the objective you&#8217;re testing for, and the impact of changes you&#8217;ve made. Only one thing is certain: the lower the traffic, the longer the wait!</p>
<p>However there are some methods to make the wait a little easier.</p>
<h2 style="color: #498edc">Take advantage of what you&#8217;ve got!</h2>
<p>A test is considered to be relevant once there have been 5,000 unique visitors and 100 conversions per variant. So focus first on pages with the highest traffic, and don&#8217;t be afraid to increase that traffic by, for example, sending a targeted email campaign to your visitors to encourage them to go to those pages. Another way to grow your traffic on those pages is to use performance-based advertising (sponsored links from Google Adwords, Facebook, and Twitter Ads, sponsored LinkedIn news, etc.). Yes, it&#8217;s a financial investment, but the certainty of generating traffic quickly is an excellent way to get reliable statistic results in less time. But that doesn&#8217;t mean you should wait for your traffic to be high before doing something! You can start by guiding your visitors through the conversion funnel right away, sending them targeted and personalized marketing messages (promotional messages, countdowns, retention pop-ins, user reactivations, sticky content on scroll, etc.).</p>
<h4 style="color: #498edc">Encourage users to act fast!</h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20349" alt="compteur" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/compteur-1024x514.jpg" width="700" height="351" /></p>
<p>The fear of missing out on a good deal is a powerful lever for getting customers to act. Displaying a running promotional countdown can create a feeling of urgency and rarity.</p>
<h2 style="color: #498edc">Don&#8217;t spread yourself too thin!</h2>
<p>The more variants you set, the more you segment your traffic, and the more time you&#8217;ll spend trying to get a reliable sample for each variant. The golden rule: no more than two variants to compare to the original. Start by testing one variant. If it outperforms the original, run a second test and compare its performance to the first variant. But be careful not to give into the temptation of multivariate tests (MVT). You don&#8217;t have the traffic for it.</p>
<h4 style="color: #498edc">Promote engagement in the conversion funnel by rewording your calls to action.</h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20352" alt="wording" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/wording.png" width="668" height="231" /></p>
<p>You can encourage users to take the next step by replacing a high-commitment verb that comes too soon with less directive wording.</p>
<p>The result in the example: A 92% increase in click rate, and an automatic improvement of 13% on overall conversion rate.</p>
<h2 style="color: #498edc">Rethink your priorities!</h2>
<p>The goal of an A/B test is often an increased conversion rate. But how do you define a conversion? Does it necessarily mean a sale? For a low-traffic test, you might instead focus on something directly linked to your main criteria, but that happens more often. So instead of looking at sales, you might, for example, target the add-to-cart rate, or the number of views for a product page. These conversion criteria are still directly linked to your main criteria (sales, in this case), but they can happen more often, which will bring you results sooner.</p>
<h4 style="color: #498edc">Increase product page views</h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20351" alt="image-product" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/image-product.png" width="732" height="229" /></p>
<p>Displaying a product in its context encourages users to discover related products, and promotes cross-selling</p>
<p>The result from the example: a 10% improvement in product page views, and a 15% increase in sales</p>
<h2 style="color: #498edc">Think big!</h2>
<p>Even with just a little traffic, be ambitious! Test changes that could have a big impact on conversions, rather than focusing on details that might result in an insignificant increase given your low traffic. Don&#8217;t be afraid to test two completely different versions of your page. With an A/B testing solution, you can change item positioning and category titles to create a page variant with a completely different design. Users will be invisibly redirected to the page. Your A/B test tool will take care of splitting the traffic and collecting statistics for each version according to the parameters that you&#8217;ve set, just like with a classic test.</p>
<h4 style="color: #498edc">Get the attention of your visitors as soon as they enter the site!</h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20350" alt="form" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/form.png" width="886" height="273" /></p>
<p>Reducing the amount of information displayed, and using catchier visual elements, will promote the call to action that leads to the sign-up form.</p>
<p>The result from the example: a 14% increase in the new visitor sign-up rate, and a 3.2% increase in the site&#8217;s overall conversion rate.</p>
<h2 style="color: #498edc">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Low traffic on your site doesn&#8217;t mean you have to give up on A/B testing. Quite the contrary. Running an A/B test campaign will force you to work in a pragmatic and structured way to get the most out of your current traffic.</p>
<h4 style="color: #498edc">About AB Tasty</h4>
<p>AB Tasty is the leading European solution for optimizing on-site and in-app conversions. It lets everyone test the effectiveness of their optimization ideas and deliver personalized experiences to their users to improve conversions. The solution runs in cloud mode. It lets marketing teams work independently to apply their ideas for optimizing their websites, mobile sites, and native applications, and measure their performance improvements without having to mobilize technical resources.<br />
AB Tasty was created five years ago. The company&#8217;s 40 employees currently work with over 200 major account customers (e-commerce sites, media sites, and lead generation sites).</p>
<p>AB Tasty is one of the 27 most innovative and fastest growing companies according to Le Pass French Tech.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.abtasty.com/" target="_blank">www.abtasty.com</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/can-start-using-ab-testing-site-low-traffic/">How can you start using A/B testing on a site with low traffic?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/can-start-using-ab-testing-site-low-traffic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Image sizes and types for PrestaShop’s default template</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/image-sizes-types-prestashops-default-template/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/image-sizes-types-prestashops-default-template/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 16:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20321</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Our first instinct when we plug in a new electronic toy is often to personalize it, from adding our own background image or customizing the homepage icons. The same reflex applies to launching and designing an online shop. Whether it’s uploading a logo or product images, the first thing we’re itching to do is make [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/image-sizes-types-prestashops-default-template/">Image sizes and types for PrestaShop’s default template</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our first instinct when we plug in a new electronic toy is often to personalize it, from adding our own background image or customizing the homepage icons. The same reflex applies to launching and designing an <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en">online shop</a>. Whether it’s uploading a logo or product images, the first thing we’re itching to do is make it all our own. To help you get your homepage personalized faster, today’s post outlines the image types and sizes you need to customize the PrestaShop default template.<br />
<span id="more-20321"></span></p>
<p><em>Updated: July 17th</em></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">Most of the pictures you upload to the back office need to be saved in a .jpeg or .png file type. If the image editing software doesn’t allow you to save the image into one of these file types, try </span><span style="font-style: italic">exporting</span><span style="line-height: 1.5"> it to one of these files.</span></p>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">Banner Block</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20332" alt="banner" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/banner-1024x56.png" width="700" height="38" /></p>
<p>The Banner block is one the first elements you’ll see on your new online store. It sits above each page of your website, so it has great visibility. Use this area to announce any major promotions that customers can’t miss!</p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: 1170 x 65 pixels</div>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">Logo</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20324" alt="logo" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/logo.jpg" width="350" height="99" /></p>
<p>The most important image on your website is your logo. The size of this image can vary slightly due to different logo designs. The maximum width allowed by the PrestaShop default theme is 370 pixels. The suggested height for this area is 52 pixels; but the theme can accommodate a height up to 65 pixels. Images taller than 65 pixels will not be scaled down which can distort the default theme.</p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: &lt; 370 x 99 pixels</div>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">Image Slider for your homepage</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20326" alt="slider" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/slider.jpg" width="779" height="448" /></p>
<p>The homepage slider is probably the second thing you noticed about your shop. The large, gorgeous images are not only attractive but move, which catches a visitor’s attention. There are 3 default images in the slideshow; we recommend having an average of 3-5 images and no more than 7.</p>
<p>SEO Tip: You can add text directly to the image, but search engines won’t be able to read it. To improve your SEO, we suggest using the built-in text overlay feature. Don’t forget to format and highlight important text with the header formatting. (Also, if you want to keep using the white text, be sure your image is dark so that the text is easy to read.)</p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: 779 x 448 pixels</div>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">Theme Configurator</h2>
<p>The theme configurator helps you add images throughout your home page. We suggest using the ones at the top (version 1) to announce current sales because they are visible even when the slider image changes. For the images towards the bottom of the page (version 2, 3 and 4), we suggest showcasing your store’s various product categories. Use corresponding images that entice online shoppers to click and explore to those types of products.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Version 1</span></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-20328" alt="theme1" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/theme1.jpg" width="381" height="219" /></p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: 381 x 219 pixels</div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic"></div>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Version 2</span></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-20394" alt="banner-img1" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/banner-img1.jpg" width="383" height="267" /></p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">
<p>Suggested Size: 383 x 267 pixels</p>
</div>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Version 3</span></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-20329" alt="theme2" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/theme2.jpg" width="383" height="142" /></p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: 383 x 142 pixels</div>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Version 4</span></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-20330" alt="theme3" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/theme3.jpg" width="777" height="142" /></p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: 777 x 142 pixels</div>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">Product Images</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20325" alt="product" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/product.jpg" width="458" height="458" /></p>
<p>The default product image will be used throughout your online shop in varying sizes. For example, product images on the product page will be larger to showcase the product but smaller on checkout when it’s just used as a reference. But don’t worry: you only have to upload the product image once while you are configuring the product. The PrestaShop software will automatically resize the images to fit with the default theme.</p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested size: 800 x 800 pixels</div>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">Watermark</h2>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-20331" alt="watermark" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/watermark.gif" width="75" height="74" /></p>
<p>Automatically add your logo to your product images to protect them from being used without giving you credit. Unlike all the other images we’ve worked with so far, you’ll need to save this image in a .gif format. You can choose to make your watermark as big or small as you’d like&#8211;just be sure it doesn&#8217;t detract from your products. The little puffin on the product image shown above is 74 x 74 pixels.</p>
<p>Tip: Want a faded watermark? Configure the opacity directly with the built in module. You’ll also get to choose where you want to position the watermark with the included module.</p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: Any<br />
Suggested Type: .gif<br />
Modules &gt; Front Office Modules &gt; Watermark</div>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">Favicon</h2>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-20322" alt="favicon" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/favicon.png" width="16" height="16" /></p>
<p>If this icon looks familiar, it’s probably because you haven’t updated your favicon to reflect your website yet. It’s located to the left of your webpage’s title and appears before every page of your online shop. There are many favicon generators that can help you transform your logo into a favicon. Be sure to save the final image as an .ico file type. If you have a very complicated logo, consider using another image to represent your online shop.</p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: 16 x 16 pixels<br />
Suggested Type: .ico<br />
Update this feature under the Preference Tab &gt; Themes &gt; Icons &gt; Favicon</div>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">Store Icon</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20327" alt="store-icon" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/store-icon.png" width="312" height="536" /></p>
<p>If you have physical locations or even resellers with physical shops, you can list them on a store locator map. This is especially helpful if you sell a product that customers would like to see in person first. The map shows customers if there’s a location nearby they can visit. Customize this page by replacing the puffin icon with your own.</p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;font-style: italic">Suggested Size: 30 x 30 pixels<br />
Suggested Type: gif<br />
Update this feature under the Preference Tab &gt; Themes &gt; Icons &gt; Store Icons</div>
<h2 style="color: #48819f">In a nutshell</h2>
<p>Once you’re familiar with the different images you need for your online shop, use this cheat sheet for help sizing them.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-20400" alt="en-image-size" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/en-image-size.png" width="636" height="389" /></p>
<p>What images are you looking forward to updating on your website? Let us know in the comments below. Not sure if PrestaShop is the right shopping cart software for you? Explore more of our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/shopping-cart">software features</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/image-sizes-types-prestashops-default-template/">Image sizes and types for PrestaShop’s default template</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/image-sizes-types-prestashops-default-template/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website evaluation: Les Minions</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/website-evaluation-les-minions/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/website-evaluation-les-minions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 10:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cécile Dubouis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20306</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Thank you to everyone who responded to our free website evaluation post. It was difficult to choose one example from among so many great stores, but we hope our advice will help everyone who reads the analysis. The first store to receive a free evaluation sells a pretty irresistible product: Minions! I&#8217;m sure many of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/website-evaluation-les-minions/">Website evaluation: Les Minions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thank you to everyone who responded to our free website evaluation post. It was difficult to choose one example from among so many great stores, but we hope our advice will help everyone who reads the analysis.</p>
<p>The first store to receive a free evaluation sells a pretty irresistible product: Minions! I&#8217;m sure many of my PrestaShop colleagues are already rushing to find the link to the store.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s take a closer look at how this French e-commerce store could optimize navigation and indexing. While there is no magic potion, the tips and best practices we suggest for each element can often be applied to other online stores too.</p>
<p>So why not try them yourself?<br />
<span id="more-20306"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #e0801c;">Navigation</h2>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Pros:</h4>
<p><a href="http://boutiqueminions.fr" target="_blank">Boutiqueminions.fr</a> has created a captivating retail universe that we plunge happily into as soon as we land on the homepage: the world of the Minions from the animated film “Despicable Me.” You can practically hear them singing Banana…</p>
<p>Most of the menu tabs on the homepage are clear and the “Promotional Pack!” tab is attention-grabbing. We can&#8217;t wait to see the products!</p>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Areas for improvement:</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Categories</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>To <strong>show the full variety of products on offer</strong>, the categories are broken down into sub-categories.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20308" alt="category" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/category.png" width="938" height="586" /></p>
<p>However, the “Miscellaneous” category (whose name could be improved) says “No product in this category,” when in fact there are plenty &#8211; the products are simply divided into the sub-categories of the “Miscellaneous” section.</p>
<div style="padding: 10px 60px; margin: 20px 0; color: #65a0e2; border: 1px solid #dce1e5;"><strong>To display products as clearly in the sub-category as in the main category,</strong> <span style="font-style: italic;">first go to each product page. Then, in the “Associations” tab, click the parent category to which the product is linked (e.g. Posters) and then the main category (e.g. Miscellaneous).</span></div>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20311" alt="Minions6EN" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/Minions6EN-1024x487.png" width="700" height="332" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Pop-up (or lightbox)</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>A lightbox pop-up appears on every page, which disrupts browsing. These pop-ups don&#8217;t advertise a flash sale or special offer, they simply tell the viewer that the store sells toys from the film.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20313" alt="pop-up" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/pop-up.png" width="994" height="863" /></p>
<p>Pop-ups are a great way of promoting a special offer, flash sale or clearance sale, <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/19431-pop-promo.html" target="_blank">as they encourage purchasing</a>. But use them sparingly, otherwise they may have the opposite effect.</p>
<div style="padding: 10px 60px; margin: 20px 0; color: #65a0e2; border: 1px solid #dce1e5;"><strong>To effectively use a lightbox pop-up on your store:</strong></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px; font-style: italic;">
<li>Enable it only during major promotions or sales events</li>
<li>Display it only on the first page visited by the user, not every page of the website</li>
</ul>
</div>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Action buttons</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The most visible call-to-action buttons should be those for finalizing an order</strong></p>
<p>At present, the “Share on Facebook” button (to receive a discount) is the most visible element on the product page and the sign-up page &#8211; at the expense of the “Add to cart” button.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20314" alt="action-buttons" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/action-buttons.png" width="938" height="629" /></p>
<p>Using a <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/social-commerce-facebook-prestashop-modules/8130-facebook-fan-coupon.html" target="_blank">Facebook Fan Coupon</a> is a great way of growing your community, but the <strong>“Add to cart” button must still be the biggest button on the page</strong>. Changing the Facebook Fan Coupon layout will resolve the problem.</p>
<p>On the <strong>order summary page</strong> (and other pages in the conversion funnel), the same amount of space is allocated to two different actions: continue shopping and place order.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20307" alt="action-buttons2" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/action-buttons2-1024x397.png" width="700" height="271" /></p>
<div style="padding: 10px 60px; margin: 20px 0; color: #65a0e2; border: 1px solid #dce1e5;"><strong>The conversion funnel</strong> <span style="font-style: italic;">describes the pages along the sales process, from order summary all the way to payment.<br />
The conversion funnel is aptly named because there is only one direction the process should follow. Each visitor that follows it should be led straight on, right to the end, until the sale is complete.</span></div>
<p>Make buttons such as “Next,” “Place Order,” “Process Payment,” etc. larger. I suggest <strong>using a lighter color for the “Continue Shopping” button</strong>, or <strong>replacing it with a simple, more discreet hyperlink</strong> if you can access the code on your site.</p>
<div style="padding: 10px 60px; margin: 20px 0; color: #65a0e2; border: 1px solid #dce1e5;"><strong>Ordering without thinking</strong><br />
<span style="font-style: italic;">The customer journey should always be clear and intuitive. From first glance, the user should know where to click to make a purchase, without having to look at the options available.</span></div>
<h2 style="color: #e0801c;">Reassurance</h2>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Pros:</h4>
<p>A quick glance at the footer shows that free delivery is available, different payment methods are accepted and contact details are provided. The live chat option allows the user to find out more information about the products &#8211; all of which boosts conversion rate!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20309" alt="footer" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/footer.png" width="1017" height="345" /></p>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Areas for improvement:</h4>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Telephone</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Don&#8217;t hesitate to display a phone number for your store if you have one (in France, companies are required to provide a non-premium phone number). Don&#8217;t worry, not every user will start calling you; but displaying a phone number can increase reassurance and therefore your conversion rate.</p>
<div style="padding: 10px 60px; margin: 20px 0; color: #65a0e2; border: 1px solid #dce1e5;"><strong>The very presence of a telephone number</strong> <span style="font-style: italic;">on your website reassures visitors. They know that if they experience a problem with their order, they can talk to someone directly over the phone. This element is even more important in the conversion funnel, in case your customers have a question about or an issue with delivery or payment.</span></div>
<h2 style="color: #e0801c;">Indexing</h2>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Pros:</h4>
<p>The names of the store and the products are clear, the URLs are rewritten and the majority are properly translated. The homepage meta-description is effective and appealing, and categories are even displayed in Google search results.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20317" alt="indexing" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/indexing.png" width="649" height="116" /></p>
<h4 style="color: #e0801c;">Areas for improvement:</h4>
<p>When we search for a product from the minions range on a search engine, the first results lead to a competitor&#8217;s store. Here are two ideas to improve indexing:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Indexing text on the homepage:</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Add a few lines at the bottom of your homepage that will improve store indexing.<br />
All you need is the native module “<strong>Home Text Editor.</strong>”<br />
Install it and write a few lines about your store, making sure to use the keywords you specified as a priority for indexing (e.g. minion toy, etc.).</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20312" alt="Minions8-EN" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/Minions8-EN-1024x552.png" width="700" height="377" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li><strong>Category titles</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>One of the main things people search for about Minions is &#8220;minion toy&#8221;. Perfect: you already have a “Toy” category&#8217;! If we look more closely at search terms, it seems they are often accompanied by an adjective, such as &#8220;large minion toy.&#8221;<br />
On the website, the “Toy” category could be divided into “Small Minion Toys” and “Large Minion Toys” in addition to the existing “Minion Figurines.”</p>
<div style="padding: 10px 60px; margin: 20px 0; color: #65a0e2; border: 1px solid #dce1e5;"><span style="font-style: italic;">Try using tools like <a href="http://www.google.fr/trends" target="_blank">Google Trends</a> to find trending search terms and use them to revise your content.</span></div>
<h2 style="color: #e0801c;">And finally&#8230;</h2>
<p>The Golden Rule: <strong>Update the customer journey</strong> regularly.<br />
<strong>Take another look at your site</strong>: create an account, search for a product, place an order and check the after-sales emails you receive, or get a friend to do it in front of you.<br />
You&#8217;ll easily find new improvements to make day after day.<br />
Lastly, congratulations on your website!<br />
Did you find these tips helpful? Let us know in the comments.<br />
Want to see your site evaluated? Send us an email at <a href="mailto:ecommerce-evaluation@prestashop.com">ecommerce-evaluation@prestashop.com</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/website-evaluation-les-minions/">Website evaluation: Les Minions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/website-evaluation-les-minions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Delivering a new and improved v1.6.1.0</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/delivering-new-improved-v1-6-1-0/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/delivering-new-improved-v1-6-1-0/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 16:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20269</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, at PrestaShop Day, we unveiled our Puffin mascot &#8211; Preston. He might be the first thing you notice about PrestaShop v1.6.1.0. However, this version brings more than just a pretty face. It boasts huge performance optimizations, enhanced EU compliance, refined tax, price calculations and more than 500 improvements. Read on to see [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/delivering-new-improved-v1-6-1-0/">Delivering a new and improved v1.6.1.0</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, at PrestaShop Day, we unveiled our Puffin mascot &#8211; Preston. He might be the first thing you notice about PrestaShop v1.6.1.0. However, this version brings more than just a pretty face. It boasts huge performance optimizations, enhanced EU compliance, refined tax, price calculations and more than 500 improvements. Read on to see all of the goodness in version 1.6.1.0!</p>
<p><span id="more-20269"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b">Back Office Facelift</span></h2>
<p>Changes to the back office are mainly cosmetic, but we managed to squeeze in a few improvements to contrast and visibility in the navigation. Essentially, we gave it a facelift. It still resembles the back office you’re used to – it’s just better. Changes include new logos, images, colors, and a few other design elements.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-large wp-image-20296" alt="new-design-B-2" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/new-design-B-2-1024x528.png" width="700" height="360" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b">Better, faster, stronger!</span></h2>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-20272" alt="prestashop-release-1.6.1.0-preston01" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/prestashop-release-1.6.1.0-preston01.png" width="147" height="223" />Borrowing from Daft Punk, we’ve made significant improvements to software performance by targeting SQL queries. We’ve made one optimization after another to ensure that your store works lightning fast! How fast you ask? Up to 200% faster at carrying out back office operations &#8211; talk about saving time!</p>
<p>This also means your website will be better equipped for traffic peaks. Great news for high traffic sale days! Get the details about our <a href="http://build.prestashop.com/news/prestashop-1-6-1-0-performances/" target="_blank">tests and results on our developer blog</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b">New Coding Standards</span></h2>
<p>We’ve reached a new chapter in PrestaShop’s coding history. To optimize the software, we adopted a new coding architecture. Moving forward, all new code contributed on GitHub should follow the <a href="http://build.prestashop.com/news/prestashop-moves-to-psr-2/" target="_blank">PSR-2 Coding Style Guide</a>. Implementing these new rules will help keep code integrity. This will also be instrumental in the unit testing process.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b">&#8220;Advanced EU Compliance&#8221; Module</span></h2>
<p>The European Union took almost a decade to form. This new union comes with a complex set of rules and regulations that can be very challenging for online merchants with international stores. Many of you have asked for features that help you meet local EU regulations, and we’ve responded! We’ve added 15 options into the “Advanced EU Compliance module” that you can use to achieve better legal compliance, faster.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-large wp-image-20293" alt="advanced-eu-compliance" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/07/advanced-eu-compliance-1024x524.png" width="700" height="358" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b">Taxes and price calculations</span></h2>
<p>No one loves taxes, but it’s at the heart of the check-out process so we spent time working on your taxes! Specifically, we refined the rounding of prices and tax management.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b">But that’s not all!</span></h2>
<p>In addition to our major fixes, we’ve refined the installation, the update process, the search function and back office controls. All bug updates can be reviewed in our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/developers-versions/changelog/1.6.1.0-stable" target="_blank">changelog</a>.</p>
<p>With this new release, we’re adopting another new practice: an updated <a href="http://build.prestashop.com/news/a-more-semantic-versioning-scheme/" target="_blank">Semantic Versioning Scheme</a>. This helps to clarify each software release and lets you see all changes faster.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b">Last but not least&#8230;</span></h2>
<p>We’d like to thank the community for all their contributions on the Forge, GitHub, Crowdin and more. We wouldn’t have gotten this far without your continued help and support! A very special shout-out to:</p>
<p><em>Adonis Karavokyros, Alessandro Corbelli, alexsimple, Antonino Di Bella, Arnaud Lemercier, Benjamin, PONGY, bercik999, Bruno Desprez, Cédric Fontaine, Dan Hlavenka, Danoosh Mir, David-Julian BUCH, Denver Prophit Jr., Desbouche Christophe, Dimitrios Karvounaris, doekia, Dvir-Julius, el-tenkova, eleazar, Eric Rouvier, Etienne Samson, fird, Francis Ramirez, Frédéric BENOIST, Germain Tenthorey, Gordon Coubrough, Guillaume Leseur, Gytis Škėma, indesign47, Jocelyn Fournier, joseantgv, Julien Deniau, Krystian Podemski, Ladel, Léo, MaX3315, natrim, Nicolas Sorosac, nodexpl, oleacorner, Pan P., pbirnzain, Pedro J. Parra, PhpMadman, PrestaEdit, Richard LT, Roland Schütz, Samy Rabih, Sébastien Monterisi, SebSept, Shagshag, Steven Sulley, Tomáš Votruba, tucoinfo, unlocomqx, vitekj, zimmi1, ZiZuu.com</em></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download the latest version of PrestaShop</a></strong> or <strong><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/create-your-online-store" target="_blank">create your PrestaShop Cloud store</a></strong> today to enjoy this new version!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/delivering-new-improved-v1-6-1-0/">Delivering a new and improved v1.6.1.0</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/delivering-new-improved-v1-6-1-0/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Support your ecommerce business with social media (Part 2 of 2)</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media-part-2-2/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media-part-2-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 16:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20262</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Have you set up your dashboard and defined the focus for your social media kit as we outlined in the last post? Yes? Great ! Let’s take a look at the final step to making your social media strategy truly unique so it stands out from other competing ecommerce businesses. 3. Match your message appeal [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media-part-2-2/">Support your ecommerce business with social media (Part 2 of 2)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you set up your <a href="https://hootsuite.com/plans?icn=primtopnav&amp;ici=Plans" target="_blank">dashboard</a> and defined the focus for your social media kit as we outlined in the last post? Yes? Great ! Let’s take a look at the final step to making your social media strategy truly unique so it stands out from other competing ecommerce businesses.<br />
<span id="more-20262"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#277083">3. Match your message appeal to your social media kit </h2>
<p>Message appeal refers to how you connect with customers to make your message resonate. Will you choose an approach based on logical reasoning or emotional pull? There are three categories of message appeal: </p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li><strong>Ethos :</strong> establish credibility using testimonials, work samples and other concrete proof</li>
<li><strong>Logos :</strong> focus on logical reasoning using facts and statistics</li>
<li><strong>Pathos :</strong> focus on emotional or motivational appeals using personal experiences, social events, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>Choose your message appeal based on the segment you want to target and the communication tools you have to encourage customers complete a specific action (for example, order a product or arrange an appointment). A careful selection is key at this stage. A <a href="http://ow.ly/L5MvI" target="_blank">recent study by HubSpot</a> confirms that message appeal has an impact on whether viewers interact with a post or not.</p>
<p>Each message appeal links to a set of Social Media tools, guided by your communication focus: </p>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/tab-en1.png"><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/tab-en1.png" alt="tab-en" width="665" height="772" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20264" /></a></p>
<p style="font-size:12px">* personal relevance, based on individual experiences, social or current events, is key to making your audience want to share your content with their business contacts, colleagues, friends and family. Example: Buzzfeed success story across social channels.</p>
<p>The key question you should ask yourself is whether a message is relevant for your target segment: What value does my post offer to them? Why should they WANT to engage?). </p>
<p>Here’s an extra tip: don’t get stuck in the ‘90s&#8211;using flashing colors, music and standardized slogans to grab attention was yesterday, online or off. Instead, carefully craft a trigger to reach your intended audience and stand out for the value you provide, not your neon font.  </p>
<h2 style="color:#277083">In a nutshell</h2>
<p>Let´s drop the theory for a minute and take a look at an e-commerce business that combines all three steps effectively: Zalando. Its global social media presence focuses on emotional and motivational appeals. The company adapts its strategy to local taste as well as to current events, which affect their narrowly defined target segments on a personal level. Zalando offers different approaches for each segment on a constant basis, as can be seen on their website. The images below reflect current accounts focused on the upcoming spring season and related emotional trigger associated with it across Facebook and Instagram: </p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-7 col-xs-12"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/zalendo1.png"><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/zalendo1-1024x526.png" alt="zalendo1" width="700" height="359" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20265" /></a></div>
<div class="col-sm-5 col-xs-12"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/zalendo2.png"><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/zalendo2.png" alt="zalendo2" width="511" height="624" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20266" /></a></div>
</div>
<p>In addition to focusing on up-to-date and coherent social interaction with potential customers, Zalando uses  complementary social ads based on cookies and online video advertising. As a result, the company has managed to become a leading global online shop representing over 1,500 brands since it was founded in 2008. </p>
<p>So how can you, as an e-commerce merchant, achieve this constant level of interaction with your target group on selected social networks? </p>
<p>The answer is, once again, focus: integrate all your social media networks on one platform!</p>
<p>Hootsuite gives you the opportunity to manage all your social media channels simultaneously via a single dashboard, making it easy for you to communicate coherently and constantly across channels, including through your e-commerce site. As shown earlier, a narrow search function allows you to follow and interact with your audience in real time, giving you a competitive edge that can make all the difference in fast-paced virtual marketspaces.</p>
<p style="font-style:italic">Not convinced yet? Start your free 30-day trial now and see for yourself if Hootsuite is the tool for you:<a href="http://ow.ly/L7QJr" target="_blank">http://ow.ly/L7QJr</a></p>
<p><strong>Written by</strong></p>
<p>Hanna Oeljeschläger (@HootHanna)<br />
Social Media Coach for DACH &amp; UK at Hootsuite</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media-part-2-2/">Support your ecommerce business with social media (Part 2 of 2)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media-part-2-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
